Álan Crístoffer e Sousa



Personal Data 30 years old, Brazilian

Contact +55 (37) 999971514

acristoffers@gmail.com https://acristoffers.me

Languages

Portuguese (native) English (C1) German (C1) French (B1)

Skills

System Analysis and Control, C/C++, Python, Kotlin, Assembly, MATLAB, Android Development, Frontend, Backend, Embedded, Automation, Robotics

Summary

Master of Science in Electrical Engineering, in the field of Control Theory, and Mechatronic Engineer with experience in system analysis and control and programming. Has worked in two scientific initiations building a platform that interfaces with hardware for system analysis and control objectives and learning Model Predictive Control.

Experience

2016-2016 **Acal BFi** Dietzenbach, Hessen, Germany

Intern

During this internship, I developed a platform to measure the power loss inside

the kernel of the inductor used in a PFC circuit.

Corpo de Bombeiros Militar de Minas Gerais 2010-2014 Divinópolis, Minas Gerais, Brazil

As a firefighter I was entitled to work as a first-aider and diver, being the first response in all sorts of accidents, from fire in the wilds to car accidents and

industrial and natural disasters.

Education

2020-2020 **Master in Electrical Engineering** CEFET-MG/UFSJ

> I developed a switching-rule for constrained switched systems based on Region of Attraction under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Valter Leite and co-supervision of Prof. Dr.

Walter Lucia.

2013-2019 **Mechatronic Engineering** Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais

> Since my first semester, I helped other students from graduation, master and PhD. with their projects, especially with programming. In my last year, I became the student

representative in the Graduation Council

2015-2016 **Student Exchange** Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences, Germany

I studied as an exchange student through the Brazilian government's program Ciências

Sem Fronteiras (Science Without Borders).

2015-2015 **Student Exchange** Université Grenoble Alpes, France

> I studied as an exchange student through the partnership between UGA and CEFET-MG. There I worked in the robotics laboratory helping the team which won the second

place in the National Instruments MyRIO Paris competition.

Extracurricular

2017 & 2018 Python mini-course Ministered

I ministered a Python mini-course at my university. The textbook (in Portuguese) is

freely available at https://acristoffers.me/assets/Python3.pdf

2017 Semana C&T - Week of Science and Technology 1st Place

My project got the first place in the 13rd workshop at my university.

2015 **National Instruments MyRIO Compatition, Paris** 2nd Place

I helped the team that got the second place in the competition. I was responsible for

the code interfacing with the camera and recognizing colors.

Latin American Robotics Competition 2014 3rd Place I was part of the team that got the third place in the competition. I was responsible for

the circuitry and programming of one of the robots.

Publications

2020	E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; SILVA, LUÍS F. P.; LUCIA, WALTER; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S. (2020). XXIII Congresso Brasileiro de Automática: Command Governor strategy based on region of attraction control switching.
2020	FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S.; COSTA, EMERSON S. (2020). XLI CILAMCE: Control Of An Oven With Space-Distributed Sensors.
2019	FILHO, MARCIO R. O.; E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; COSTA, EMERSON S.; LEITE, VALTER J. DE S. (2019). XL IBERO-LATIN AMERICAN CONGRESS ON COMPUTATIONAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING: Prototype Modelling for Real Systems.
2018	E SOUSA, ÁLAN C.; LEITE, VALTER J. S.; RUBIO SCOLA, IGNACIO. Affordable Control Platform with MPC Application. Studies in Informatics and Control, v. 27, p. 265-274, 2018.
2017	LOPES, A. N. D.; LEITE, V. J. S.; SILVA, L. F. P.; e Sousa, Álan. ESTABILIZAÇÃO LOCAL DE SISTEMAS NÃO-LINEARES VIA MODELAGEM FUZZY TAKAGI-SUGENO DISCRETA NO TEMPO. In: Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente (SBAI), 2017, Porto Alegre - RS. XIII Simpósio Brasileiro de Automação Inteligente, 2017.

Interests

System Analysis and Control Theory I worked with constrained switched systems and MPC. I studied non-linear and robust control, positive polynomials in control and complex networks.

Programming C/C++, Python, Julia, Kotlin, Rust, Ruby, MATLAB...Languages are just tools in the belt. I can program using structured, object oriented and functional paradigms. I always try to use design patterns to make the code more organized and maintainable.